Guide to the Great composers and musicians collection,
Great composers and musicians collection,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Great composers and musicians collection,
4674
58 items.
Autographs, manuscripts, and portraits.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Autographs, brief music manuscripts, and/or portraits of famous Western European and American composers and performers, including Beethoven, Berlioz, Brahms, Busoni, Elgar, Gounod, Grieg, Handel, Haydn, Liszt, MacDowell, Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer, Mozart, Paderewski, Paganini, Rossini, Anton Rubinstein, Saint-Saëns, Sarasate, Schubert, Sibelius, Richard Strauss, Tchaikovsky, Toscanini, Verdi, Wagner, Weber, and Hugo Wolf. The bound volume includes autographs, manuscript letters, and/or portraits of composers including Beethoven, Brahms, Chopin, Dvorak, Gounod, Grieg, Francis Scott Key, Leoncavallo, Liszt, Massenet, Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer, Offenbach, Rossini, Saint-Saëns, Schumann, Verdi, and Wagner.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Autographs, brief music manuscripts, and/or portraits of famous Western European and American composers and performers, including Beethoven, Berlioz, Brahms, Busoni, Elgar, Gounod, Grieg, Handel, Haydn, Liszt, MacDowell, Mendelssohn, Meyerbeer, Mozart, Paderewski, Paganini, Rossini, Anton Rubinstein, Saint-Saëns, Sarasate, Schubert, Sibelius, Richard Strauss, Tchaikovsky, Toscanini, Verdi, Wagner, Weber, and Hugo Wolf. T
p>
SUBJECTS
Names:
Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827.; Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869.; Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897.; Busoni, Ferruccio, 1866-1924.; Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934.; Gounod, Charles, 1818-1893.; Grieg, Edvard, 1843-1907.; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759.; Haydn, Joseph, 1732-1809.; Liszt, Franz, 1811-1886.; MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908.; Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847.; Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1791-1864.; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791.; Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941.; Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840.; Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868.; Rubinstein, Anton, 1829-1894.; Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921.; Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908.; Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828.; Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957.; Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949.; Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893.; Toscanini, Arturo, 1867-1957.; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901.; Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883.; Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826.; Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903.
Subjects:
Composers -- France.; Composers -- Germany.; Composers -- Italy.; Composers -- Great Britain.; Musicians.; Musicians -- Portraits.; Music -- History and criticism -- 18th century.; Music -- History and criticism -- 19th century.
Form and Genre Terms:
Autographs (manuscripts).; Portraits.; Criticism, interpretation, etc.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Related item: The great composers: a collection of autographs, 1842-1910, #4600 Bd. Ms. 695.
CONTAINER LIST
- Rossini, Gioachino Antonio, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Paderewski, Ignacy Jan, 1896-1905-04-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Strauss, Richard, 1894-02-22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  letter undated, fragment 1894
- Berlioz, Hector, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Godard, Benjamin Louis Paul, 1888-11-02 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Brahms, Johannes, 1874-12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sibelius, Jean, 1907-07-04 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Elgar, Sir Edward, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Paganini, Nicolo, 1831-07-05 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Tschaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1894-03-19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Thalberg, Sigismond, 1842-12-12 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Saint-Saens, Camille, 1879-04-21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  On reverse, fragment by Benjamin Godard
- Glazunov, Alexander Constantinovich, 1897-07-03 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Romberg, Bernard, 1826-02-19 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Sainton, Philip, 1885-11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Koschat, Thomas, 1910-04-27 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Sarasate, Pablo Martin, 1873-05-06 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Schubert, Franz Peter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Rubenstein, Anton Gregor, 1870-03-30 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Gounod, Charles Franois, 1839-12-01 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Meyerbeer, Giacomo, 1857-07-1861-10-19 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  letter 1861, fragment 1857
- D"Albert, Eugne Francis, 1890-05-13 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Bruch, Max, 1874-04-02-1892-05-24 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  letter 1874, fragment 1892
- Wolf, Ferrari Ermano, 1906-03-16 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Moszkowski, Moritz, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- von Suppe, Franz, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Goldmark, Karl, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Busoni, Ferruccio Benvenuto, 1900-05 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Chaminade, Ccile, 1919-02 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Vieuxtemps, Henri, 1870-10 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Pacini, Giovanni, 1837-10-14 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Grieg, Edvard, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Wagner, Wilhelm Richard, 1876-08-13 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Joachim, Joseph, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Halll, Sir Charles, 1888-09-19-1890-04-10 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  letter 1888, fragment 1890
- MacDowell, Edward Alexander, 1892-10-31 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- d'Indy, Paul Marie, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Weber, Carl Maria Friedrich Ernst von, 1863-07-08 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Liszt, Franz, 1845-04-10 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Clementi exercises copied by Jose Ranieri Raymond Villanova, annotated by Liszt
- Haydn, Joseph, 1825-08-01 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  sketch of portrait
- Handel, George Frederick, 1789-01-01 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  sketch of Vauxhall statue
- Handel, George Frederick, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  sketch of 1725-1759 house
- Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1770-1775 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Mascagni, Pietro, 1903-04-08 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Wagner, Richard, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Beethoven, Ludwig van, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Toscanini, Arturo, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  Carnegie Hall program
- Toscanini, Arturo, 1936-04-29 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  autographed Philharmonic-Symphony Society of New York program
- Weber, Carl Maria von, 1820-11-03 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Cherubini, Luigi, 1806-1839 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  letters dated 1806-03-23, 1828-10-18, 1831; Solfege dated 1839-06
- Wolf, Hugo, 1891-05-08 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Verdi, Giuseppe, 1868-05-24 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Wolf, Hugo, 1889-1890 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1841-07-09 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Moore, Thomas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  poem set to music by Henry A. Bishop, portrait dated 1832
- Kullak, Theodor, 1853-03-24-1872-03-07 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  letter 1853, fragment 1872
- Williams, Ralph Vaughan, 1954-11-09 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- MacDowell, Edward Alexander, 1891-01-05 (Box 1, Folder 58)